Omar Lozada



Full stack developer with 8+ years of experience, occasionally speaker at tech events in Peru and doer at all.

1458 Gaylord st. Apt. 5, 80206, Denver, Colorado US

Hello,

Let me introduce myself, my name is Omar. Currently, I'm a software Developer. I specialize in JavaScript, particularly Full Stack Developer with Node.js and Ruby on Rails. The position I obtain with this company has helped me develop many apps and websites using edge technologies such as: Ionic, Tailwindcss, Angular, React, React Native, Flutter, Firebase, Node, MongoDb, etc. Before this experience, I built my own tech company in Peru an agency that helped clients build versatile platforms for their businesses. I'm 29 and currently located in Chiclayo, Peru. For any further questions about my credentials, I'm available

WORK EXPERIENCE (9)

Full-Stack Software Engineer at Able September 2021- May 2022 https://able.co/

Full-time remote job as a Full-Stack Software Engineer, web and mobile projects

for video calls and any emails about my skills, personality, and references.

- https://10east.co/ build a platform for a community of private investors
- https://updater.com/ upgrade of the sales platform

Full-Stack Software Engineer at ITCRAFTSHIP SP. Z O.O. (Poland) June 2020- July 2021 https://itcraftship.com/

Full-time remote job as a Full-Stack Software Engineer, web and mobile projects

- Sundose https://sundose.io/ Sundose is an alternative to outdated mass-produced supplementation (Flutter)
- storysurf https://storysurf.app/ Because whatever you're feeling, there's a story for that. (Flutter)
- Friendly Fire, is a game to play with friends around the world. (React Native / Firebase)

JS Lead at Velocis LLC, (USA) February 2016- March 2020 http://velocis.us

Full-time remote job, web developer, receive tasks/projects through a third party company and complete in a timely manner.

- Skyrise http://skyriseapp.com/ app to connect entire building and small companies within to help communicate on a single platform if needed.
- Aldea http://aldeaapp.com/ app collaborated with skyrise, but used for residences and staff for apartment buildings.
- Student Success Academy https://studentsuccess.co/ a platform to help high school students chose a career in their final years.
- Nomadic http://nomadic-app.co/ app to help link and connect van travelers.

http://twitter.com/yetsuPe

Co Founder & CTO of Yetsu S.A.C. Our agency helped develop websites for clients. The main focus and objection were to create platforms for clients to their satisfaction. With the diversity of web development from restaurants, hotels, and marketing facebook campaigns for two companies, our agency created a vast of platforms.

- Development a web with eCommerce focus for XCOREISC
- Enterprise software for CONSAMA.S.A.C.
- I was the instructor of 2 courses for this company and sponsored by UNPRG.

President at X COREISC May 2015- May 2015

https://www.facebook.com/XCOREISC

Led a large team composed of more than 60 persons for a week-long conference called COREISC, a tech event for computer-science enthusiasts in the north-region of Peru.

Cheif and team leader that organized the people into 5 groups: marketing (social network), sales (promote and sale the events and tickets), protocol (conference usher, event coordinator, personal assistant), IT (build the website for the conference to purchase tickets on), legal (taxes, legal documents for the conference, and official/legal invitations).

- +500 attenders
- First Event of APEISC(brand's owner) with online payments(paypal and credit cards)
- New sub events created like battle of startups, ignites, hackaton, etc.

UNPRG Represent (Student Representative) at APEISC November 2011- August 2014 http://www.apeisc.org/

APEISC (currently known as APECIT), is the largest and official community for all students of Software Engineering and computer-science in Peru. Once a year an immense amount of Universities from around the country would choose two students to represent them.

This organization was given certain responsibilities to contribute to the computer science community in the country and help promote events and activities to encourage college students to keep growing up in their tech careers.

- Delagado fraterno 2013 -2014
- Delegado Pleno 2014

Teacher at YETSU S.A.C. & UNPRG April 2013- May 2013

https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.163394703820870.1073741828.112843935542614&type=3

Course about web development realized at UNPRG

- Syllabus https://github.com/YetsuPe/yetsu-Template/blob/v1.0/curso/Diplomado--Desarrollo-de-Aplicaciones-Web-Yetsu-UNPRG-2013.pdf
- Photos: https://www.facebook.com/media/set/? set=a.163394703820870.1073741828.112843935542614&type=3

Second course, this course had frontend technologies as main aim

Examples and material https://github.com/YetsuPe

Junior Developer at Mac Systems Group S.C.R.Lta. **February 2010- June 2011** https://www.facebook.com/Mac-Systems-Group-SCRLta-168661576491011/

Junior developer for Mac System Group, a local company in Lambayeque.

First steps in real projects.

VOLUNTEER

Coach at Startup Weekend

September 2014 - September 2014

http://www.up.co/communities/peru/ica/startup-weekend/3763

Startup Weekends are weekend-long, hands-on experiences where entrepreneurs and aspiring entrepreneurs can find out if startup ideas are viable. On average, half of Startup Weekend's attendees have technical or design backgrounds, the other half have business backgrounds. Beginning with open mic pitches on Friday, attendees bring their best ideas and inspire others to join their team. Over Saturday and Sunday teams focus on customer development, validating their ideas, practicing LEAN Startup Methodologies and building a minimal viable product. On Sunday evening teams demo their prototypes and receive valuable feedback from a panel of experts.

Teacher at hack Space

June 2015 - June 2015

https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.1010950065581848.1073741857.854008687942654&type=3

Taught the course, "Web Fundamentals and Javascript for Everyone" at University Pedro Ruiz Gallo as a programming teacher for half a semester.

Speaker at FLISOL 2013

May 2013 - May 2013

https://www.facebook.com/flisolLambayeque/photos/a.550858391631871.1073741826.176772925707088/550867084964335/?type=3&theater

Public speaker invitation for the Flisol Conference, to lecture about MongoDB and no-sql databases.

President at CADIS-UNPRG
March 2013 - March 2014

https://www.facebook.com/CADIS.UNPRG

CADIS is a internal organization dedicated to investigation of many topics subjects for Ti/Software students

Speaker at UNASAM

November 2013 - November 2013

I talked about html5 and its features, this event was realized during Engineering faculty anniversary of UNSAM

- Few photos: https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=690816484263805&set=a.462104847134971.110808.100000063796163&type=3&theater
- Huaráz is a nice place.

Speaker at USAT

November 2013 - November 2013

https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?

fbid=521289761216479&set=a.462104847134971.110808.100000063796163&type=3&theater

Lecture about bootstrap framework and less preprocessor

Instructor at INTERSYS-UNPRG

November 2012 - November 2012

https://www.facebook.com/Intersys.unprg/photos/pb.237361496310516.-2207520000.1449485655./449464925100171/?type=3&theater

workshop "creación de diapositivas con html5"

Teacher at CADIS-UNPRG
July 2012 - July 2012

course about html5 y css3

few photos: https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?
fbid=462105187134937&set=a.462104847134971.110808.100000063796163&type=3&theater

SPEAKER at FLISOL - ICA 2014

April 2014 - April 2014

I talked about ruby and ruby on rails, and how to start with rvm.

photos:

https://www.facebook.com/devacademyla/photos/a.498644203569333.1073741856.316005858499836/498647610235659/? type=3&theater

Guest host at DevAcademy

April 2015 - April 2015

https://www.facebook.com/devacademyla/photos/pb.316005858499836.-2207520000.1449486341./645566912210394/?type=3&theater

"javascript para todo"

Coach at Startup CIX

February 2014 - February 2014

https://www.facebook.com/startupchiclayo/

Advisor for entrepreneurs to take the proper steps towards building their business. I would guide the clients with support teams to help develop their apps and companies.

4 year Ingeniería de Sistemas at Universidad Nacional Pedro Ruíz Gallo 2009 - 2013 LANGUAGES English spanish fluent speaker native speaker INTERESTS Web development vegan life es6 react angular node.js healty life

REFERENCES

ruby on rails redux

mongo db

EDUCATION (1)

"Omar joined Velocis and our remote team as a very green junior developer. I've been very impressed with how he has pushed himself to progress over the years and how his skills have improved. Omar is also the most loyal employee that I've ever worked with and this is a quality I value immensely. I would recommend Omar for any developer role that will continue to support his growth."

Bradley Joyce, CEO Velocis LLC

firebase

ionic

mongodb